JUAN L GALEAZZI

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER/ FRONT END ENGINEER/ DATA ANALYST

jgaleazzi@gmail.com 713 298 9124 Austin, TX

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with over 10 years of experience developing a wide range of web applications and front-end solutions using a full range of tools and technologies spanning from simple html - based pages to the implementation of sophisticated web apps. Highly skilled in integrating backend, third party API's website maintenance and troubleshooting etc. by deploying a wide range of technologies across multiple frameworks, ensuring compatibility with all major browsers and platforms.

More recently I took the Data Analysis and visualization program at the University of Texas at Austin to complement and expand my career as a developer.

KEY SKILLS

- Web Development & Maintenance
- API integration
- Front End Programming (JS)
- Video Integration
 Software Development
- API Development
- Prototyping

- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Requirements Gathering
- IoT integration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- OS: Windows/ Mac OS/ Linux
- Languages: JavaScript(ES6), Python 3.6, Swift, C/C++/C#
- Web Development & design: HTML5/CSS3,
- Frameworks: ReactJS, Redux, jquery, Bootstrap, D3
- GIS: Esri , Leaflet
- Python Libraries: Pandas, MatplotLib, Beautiful Soup, Flask, TensorFlow.
- Databases: SQL MySQL, MySQL Lite, NoSQL Mongo
- Other: Git, Bitbucket, SVN, Tableau, Excel, VBA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Texas Department of Public Safety, Austin TX

Software Engineer TXMap. (Aug 2011 - Present);

Implement JavaScript GIS solutions utilizing ESRI and Leafleft API's

Implement new Features and requests for Mapping utilities.

React/Redux implementation of Mapping application.

Design and Development of Modules and Widgets, for use in Flex and JavaScript based GIS applications for Law Enforcement.

Verizon VSO, Irving TX.

Sr. Flex Developer (Consultant with Newt Global) Apr 2011 – July 2011

Flex Front end development of modules and classes using RobotLegs framework for creating and managing Virtual Machines

40ver Inc., Glendale Ca,

Sr. Flex Developer. Sep 2010 – March 2011

Develop online design and printing applications.

Walt Disney Co. (Disney Internet Group) North Hollywood CA

Web Developer (contract), Disney Online Studios (contract) Aug 2009 – Apr 2010

Develop and update features for pixiehollow.com website.

HTML and CSS rewrite of flash based website

HTML and CSS implementation of email blasts

Eveo Inc. San Francisco, CA.

Sr. Flex Developer (contract) Mar 2009 - June 2009

Flex applications using PureMVC framework.

Adobe Systems Inc. San Francisco CA.

Sr. Flash Developer, Adobe Multimedia Studio, Aug 2008 – Feb 2009

Develop Flex-AIR Video Closed Captioning Application.

Created Flash based video Marquees for use in the Adobe products web sites.

Continental Vista Broadcasting Group/ Whiteblox Inc. (The Woodlands, TX)

Web Development Manager, April 2004 to May 2008

Oversee Flash and Actionscript Development of the Flash Team.

Develop custom reusable components for Flex/Actionscript 3.0 for use in Indycar's streaming player.

Integrate live streaming video form third parties CDN's such as Akamai and Limelight Networks.

Integrate The Indycar's player with Flash Media Server for real time scoring and messaging

Create a Flex/Actionscript client for a third party chat Server-solution based on .ASP (cutesofts .net chat)

Integrate Whiteblox Players with third party API's

Interview and recommend Hiring of actionscript developers to form the Flash Development group.

Created the Whiteblox version 2.0 player, which consisted of a reusable swf, that was skinned and configured at runtime using XML and CSS, stylesheets

Create reusable modules/components for use in the version 2 player. such as chat, polls, messaging and tickers among others. Connect the player with data sources using a variety of methods such as Flash Remoting, Socket server calls XML calls and Web Services among other.

Maquinaria Creativa. (Mexico City)

Contract Flash Developer, July 2002 to Jan 2003

Architect and develop training modules for use in web based Interactive education, for the National Institute of Adult Education in Mexico.

Create simple drag and drop games and puzzles for use in the Education Modules

Oversee Flash design and development efforts from other designers.

Pennebaker LMC (Houston, TX)

Multimedia Developer, July 2000 to June 2002

Program and Develop Interactive Cd-Roms using Macromedia Director

Develop HTML and Flash Based sites for Pennebaker's clients as well for Internal Marketing

Update content for the Compaq Computer Corp. IMC intranet (Internal Marketing Communications)

Contract Development (Mexico City)

Freelance and contract multimedia developer, July 1997 to May 2000

Create, developed and oversee design of Interactive CD-Based Annual Reports and Marketing pieces for major Mexican corporations such as Banamex, Elektra and grupo Televisa.

Grupo Intersys (Mexico City)

Systems Engineer, January 1995 to January 1996

Internal Network Administration, Hardware Installation

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

2018-2019	Certificate in Data Analysis and Visualization, McCombs School of Business, University of Texas at Austin
2010-2014	BS Financial Computer Systems - Universidad TecMilenio
2009	Adobe Flex 3 with AIR certified Expert
2003	Macromedia Certified Professional - Flash MX
1996	Certificate in multimedia production ,Vancouver Film School, Vancouver B.C. Canada
1990 – 1994	Computer systems for Administration . ITESM, Mexico city campus, Mexico city Mexico